Roham Shojaei - Full Stack Developer

E-Mail: rohamwork1@gmail.com | Phone: +989388391302 | Skype: hassan.shojaei | Address: Iran(Open to relocation)

Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/roham0010

SUMMARY

I am a Full Stack Developer with 10 years of experience in web development, specializing in PHP, Laravel, JavaScript, TypeScript, Docker, CI/CD tools, and cloud technologies like AWS. My expertise extends to databases with MySQL, PostgreSQL, Redis, and RDS, as well as developing complex JavaScript applications. I have co-founded projects and led development teams, mentored and evaluated junior developers, and continuously expanded my technical skills. I am open to remote opportunities and willing to relocate for the right position.

SKILLS

PHP, JavaScript, TS, React.js Angular.js, Vue.js, HTML5, CSS3 Languages: Frameworks: Laravel Codelgniter, Symfony (Aspiring) Databases: MySQL, PostgreSQL, Redis RDS, Firebase, CloudServices Tools: AWS, Docker, Jenkins, CI/CD, YAML, Git, PHPUnit, Jira XDebug, Kubernetes CLI, Linux

Practices: Agile, SOLID, Design Patterns, RESTful API GraphQL, MVC, OOP, TDD, CI/CD, Integrations

Exploring: Java, Python, Node.js

EDUCATION

Bachelor's Degree in Computer Software Engineering

2010 - 2014 Sadjad University of Mashhad

WORK EXPERIENCES



Medical Leave, GymHub (Jul 2023 - Present)

Home

I had Orthognathic Jaw Surgery and after that started GymHub as Co-Founder and CTO targeting Gym goers to motivate them not to quit the Gym and attend classes.

- Designed and developed the RestfulAPI for the mobile app and wrote feature tests and unit tests.
- Used **GitHub Actions** for the **CI/CD** and created the **production** environment.
- Used **Docker** and **dockerized** the Admin and API projects.
- Automated the creation of the API docs using OpenAPI Specification(OAS).

뤮 Full Stack at Artbees, Growmatik (Sep 2020 − Jul 2023)

Remote

Growmatik is a marketing automation platform that helps businesses grow their online presence and sales by personalizing their website, sending emails, showing popups, and many other marketing tools.

- In an agile environment, Mentored and Evaluated Developers, Reviewed Code, engaged in Sprint Planning, did Pair Programming, engaged in CI/CD, Practiced TDD, and contributed to Retrospectives, and User Support.
- Built and maintained an email service (email campaigns) with AWS SES and SNS to send emails to 10+ million unique emails, achieving a bounce rate of <0.5% and a spam rate of <0.03% with millions of emails sent.
- Designed and implemented Growmatik's core services, Workflow, Automation, and Simple Rule Engine, handling real-time execution of thousands of Automation and Workflow's complex big queries, and increasing customer targeting and stickiness by 30%.
- Accelerated the JS script engine for running front-end actions and triggers(popup, page personalization,..) by refactoring it to decrease size and increase speed.
- Boosted Growmatik customer targeting with Shopify integration, increasing our customers by 35% in 2 months.
- Doubled customers by integrating Growmatik with services like AWS, WP, Stripe, HubSpot, SparkPost, DKIM and SPF authorizations, GSC, GDS, FB, and more, expanding the platform's functionality and compatibility.
- Estimated and Delivered tasks by deadlines, filled reports, and attended everyday stand-up meetings.

Googsell and Emenu were online platforms that aimed to create online stores for Instagram shops and QR code menus for restaurants and coffee shops by integrating with Instagram API (Both were shut down after Instagram filtering in Iran).

- Ranked top 5 for the best online store out of 4000 participants in the Iran Web and Mobile Festival in 2017.
- Managed the team to establish the main Instagram API integration for Googsell.com and Emenu.io, integrating the pages and converting them to websites with only 5 clicks.
- Grew Googsell to **over 500 Instagram shops** in the first years.
- Led, Designed Solutions, Reviewed Codes, and Debugged code using various tools and technologies.

Full Stack/Senior Developer at 2nabsh.com (Jun 2015 – Dec 2017)

On-site

2nabsh is one of the biggest realtor SaaS apps in Iran, that provides online platforms for real estate agents and buyers.

- Planned and collaborated in project migration from pure PHP to Laravel 5.5, and automated the database conversion, saving 50% time.
- Created a web crawler that identified and integrated new properties from our contractors, resulting in a decrease in realtor bounce rate, also increasing Google click rate by 15%.
- O Built part of the **OAuth 2** with Laravel Passport on Restful API and **integrated realtors' websites**.

A Software Engineer at Dayamooz.com Company (2014-2015)

On-site

Daya is the biggest educational social media and gamification learning app in Iran, that helps students learn and interact with each other online.

- As a back-end developer, worked part-time at Daya company on their microservices for the mobile app.
- I also learned Java Spring, and Hibernate to work needed for a RestAPI part of the project.

🗐 Co-Founder, BackEnd Developer at Espida.net (2013-2014)

On-site

Espida.net was a company that provided software and network services to various customers. I developed a **Custom CMS** in PHP to develop and maintain our projects.

We provided software to various companies, such as staff attendance for a military base, a tourism website
for a municipality organization, CRM for a hardware recovery store, and a support tracking system for a
computer accessory shop.

FullStack Developer at Freelancer

On-site, Remote

A short list of freelancing work that I have done during my whole career, I have mostly used Jenkins and Github Actions for CI/CD, Sometimes dockerized projects, and always asked and suggested writing tests.

- O Serverless Payment and Staff Management APP with React Native and Firebase.
- API for a **Car Parking Finder** project by React Native and the Lara GPS Device using Java Spring and Hibernate.
- Assembled a fully-fledged Cryptocurrency Trading website.
- Refactored and expanded a Telegram Bot API marketplace with tens of menus and actions, increasing the
 user base of the bot to over 200K and handling millions of user requests per month with a simple VPS.
- Free and open-source **Chrome extension** that shows new Persian poems via push notification.
- Some others: Established a Lottery website and support of municipality tourism website.

Languages: Conversational English, fluent Persian, and exploring Deutsch.

Hobbies: Futsal, Volleyball, Pingpong.

Soft Skills: Strong problem-solving, Multi-tasking, <u>Lazyness</u>, Easily adopting new technologies, Fast learning, MVP-oriented if necessary.